<glossary xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="rs_glossary" version="5.0" role="auto">
    <title>Glossary</title>
    <info>
      <legalnotice>
          <para>
              Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
              you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
              You may obtain a copy of the License at
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    <link xlink:href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0">http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0</link>
	  </para>
	  <para>
              Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
              distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
              WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
              See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
              limitations under the License.
	  </para>
      </legalnotice>
    </info>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>A</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>API</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Acronym for Application Programming Interface. An API allows independent programmers to develop newly created application services, using an open application.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Apache</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The most common web server software presently being used on the Internet.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Applet</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Java program that can be embedded into a web page.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>application server</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A piece of software that makes available another piece of software over a
                        network.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>ASPs</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Acronym for Application Service Providers. These are companies that
                        rent specialized applications that help businesses and organizations provide
                        additional services at lower cost.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>B</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>backup schedule</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>
                    A backup schedule can be defined to create server
                    images at regular intervals (daily and weekly). Backup
                    schedules are configurable per server.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>bandwidth</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The amount of available data used by communication resources such as the
                    Internet. It refers the amount of data that is used to download things or the
                    amount of data available to download.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>binary</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Information that consists solely of ones and zeroes, which is the language of
                    computers.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
            <glossentry>
                <glossterm>bit</glossterm>
                <glossdef>
                    <para>Is a single digit number that’s in base of 2 (either a zero or one).
                        Bandwidth usage is measured in bits-per-second.</para>
                </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>bit torrent</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A peer-to-peer system that legally shares files such as legal software
                    updates, movies and other resources.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>blog</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Refers to an online journal. Blogs can be either personal or professional in
                    tone.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>BPS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Acronym for for bit-per-second, the most universal measurement of how quickly data
                    is transferred from place to place.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>browser</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Any client software that allows a computer or device to access the Internet
                    (Microsoft Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome, etc…).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
                <glossterm>byte</glossterm>
                <glossdef>
                    <para>Set of bits that make up a single character there are usually 8 bits to a
                        byte.</para>
                </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>C</title>
        <glossentry>
                <glossterm>Certificate Authority</glossterm>
                <glossdef>
                    <para>Issuer of online security certificates that shows if a web site is
                        verified as safe.</para>
                </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>cloud computing</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Cloud computing is a set of pooled computing resources delivered over the
                    Internet.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
            <glossentry>
                <glossterm>cloudware</glossterm>
                <glossdef>
                    <para>Refers to software that only exists on the Internet. There is no material
                        product that resides on your computer or disks.</para>
                </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>connection logging</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The connection logging feature allows logs to be delivered to a Cloud Files
                    account every hour. For HTTP-based protocol traffic, these are Apache-style access
                    logs. For all other traffic, this is  connection and transfer logging.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>cookie</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Information that web pages save and send back as a way to recognize a user so
                    that on succeeding visits, the users are recognized.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>cyberspace</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Refers to the Internet and all the information stored on it.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>D</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>DHTML</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Acronym for Dynamic HyperText Markup Language. Used to refer to pages that use
                        HTML, JavaScript. and CCS to allow users to interact with a web page or show
                        simple animation.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>download</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The transfer of data – usually in the form of files – from one computer to
                    another.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>DNS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
               <para> Acronym for Domain Name System. DNS is a system that translates
                human readable computer hostnames or domain names (for example, www.rackspace.com) into the
                IP addresses that networking equipment needs for delivering information. It also stores other 
                information, such as the list of mail exchange servers that accept e-mail for a given domain. 
                In providing a worldwide keyword-based redirection service, DNS is an essential component of 
                contemporary Internet use. </para> 
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>DNS Record</glossterm>
            <glossdef><para>A record that specifies information about a particular domain.</para></glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>domain</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>On the Internet, a name that identifies a web site.  
                Domains organize network addresses into hierarchical subsets. For example, the .com domain 
                identifies web sites that are used for commercial business.  </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
       
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Domain Name System</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para<See DNS.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>domain owner</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>For Rackspace DNS, the account that creates the domain is the domain
                    owner.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
       
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>duck</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An aquatic bird.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>E</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>email</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>System for transferring messages from one computer to another over the Internet.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>F</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>firewall</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>System that prevents unauthorized access to a computer or a network. Firewalls control 
                incoming and outgoing network traffic by analyzing each packet 
                and determining whether it should be allowed through, based on a predetermined rule set.  Firewalls
                can be hardware-based, software-based, or a combination of hardware and software.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Flash</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Technology that is used for Internet animation, developed by
                    Macromedia.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>flavor</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>
                    A flavor is a system configuration for a
                    cloud server. Each flavor has a unique combination of disk
                    space, memory capacity and priority for CPU time. 
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>FTP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Acronym for File Transfer Protocol. A method of moving files between
                    two separate sites on the Internet.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>G</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>gateway</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Hardware or software that connects two or more networks, converting data to the  
                protocol understood by each network.  </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>GIF</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Acronym for Graphic Interchange Format, a type of image file that is commonly
                    used for animated images on web pages.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>H</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>hacker</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An intruder who attempts to enter a site for the purpose of causing
                    intentional damage.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
         <glossterm>health monitor</glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>A feature of each load balancer that is used to determine
                whether a back-end node is usable for processing a request. The load
                balancing service supports two types of health monitors: passive and active. </para>
        </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>homepage</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>(1) The main page for any website. (2) The first page a browser loads when it opens.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>host</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A computer and/or network facility that stores data that is available to be
                    accessed by other computers.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>HTML</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Stands for HyperText Markup Language, the coding that creates documents for
                    use on the Internet.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>HTTP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Stands for HyperText Transfer Protocol, the protocol that tells browsers where
                    to go to find information.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>hypertext</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Any kind of text that contains a link to some other site, commonly found in
                    documents where clicking on a word or words opens up a different web
                    site.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>I</title>
       <glossentry>
            <glossterm>image</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>
                    An image is a collection of files used to create or
                    rebuild a server. Rackspace provides a number of
                    pre-built OS images by default.  You may also create
                    custom images from cloud servers you have launched.
                    These custom images are useful for backup purposes or
                    for producing “gold” server images if you plan to
                    deploy a particular server configuration frequently.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>IP address</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Number that’s unique to every computer system on the Internet.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>ISP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Refers to Internet Service Provider, which is any business that provides
                    Internet access to individuals or businesses.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>J</title>
   
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Java</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A programming language that is used to create systems that involve more than
                    one computer by way of a network.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Javascript</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A programming language used in web pages.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>K</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>L</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>load balancer</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A load balancer is a logical device which belongs to a cloud account. It is used
                    to distribute workloads between multiple back-end systems or services, based on the
                    criteria defined as part of its configuration.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>M</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>N</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>node</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A node is a back-end device providing a service on a specified IP and port.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>P</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>Q</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>R</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Rackspace Cloud DNS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Domain Name System (DNS) available to Rackspace Cloud customers.
                    Interactions with Rackspace Cloud DNS occur programmatically via the Rackspace
                    Cloud DNS API as described in this Cloud DNS Developer Guide.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>reboot</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>
                    The reboot function allows for either a soft or hard
                    reboot of a server. With a soft reboot, the operating
                    system is signaled to restart, which allows for a
                    graceful shutdown of all processes. A hard reboot is
                    the equivalent of power cycling the server.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>rebuild</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>
                    
                    The rebuild function removes all data on the server
                    and replaces it with the specified image. Server ID
                    and IP addresses remain the same.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>record</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> A DNS record belongs to a particular domain and is used to specify information
                    about the domain. There are several types of DNS records. Each record type contains
                    particular information used to describe that record's purpose. Examples include mail
                    exchange (MX) records, which specify the mail server for a particular domain, and
                    name server (NS) records, which specify the authoritative name servers for a domain. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>resize</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>
                    The resize function converts an existing server to a
                    different flavor, in essence, scaling the server up or
                    down. The original server is saved for a period of
                    time to allow rollback if there is a problem. All
                    resizes should be tested and explicitly confirmed, at
                    which time the original server is removed. All resizes
                    are automatically confirmed after 24 hours if they are
                    not confirmed or reverted.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        
            <glossentry>
                <glossterm>RESTful</glossterm>
                <glossdef>
                    <para>A kind of web service API that uses REST, or Representational State
                        Transfer.  REST is the style of architecture for hypermedia systems that is
                        used for the  World Wide Web.</para>
                </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>S</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>server</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Computer that provides explicit services to the client software running on
                    that system, often managing a variety of computer operations.</para>
                 <para>        
                    A server is a virtual machine instance in the Cloud
                    Servers system. Flavor and image are requisite
                    elements when creating a server.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>session persistence</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Session persistence is a feature of the load balancing service. It attempts to
                    force subsequent connections to a service to be redirected to the same node as long
                    as it is online. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>shared IP address</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>
                    Public IP addresses can be shared across multiple
                    servers for use in various high availability
                    scenarios. When an IP address is shared to another
                    server, the cloud network restrictions are modified to
                    allow each server to listen to and respond on that IP
                    address (you may optionally specify that the target
                    server network configuration be modified).  Shared IP
                    addresses can be used with many standard heartbeat
                    facilities (e.g. keepalived) that monitor for failure
                    and manage IP failover.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>shared IP group</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>
                    A shared IP group is a collection of servers that can
                    share IPs with other members of the group.  Any server
                    in a group can share one or more public IPs with any
                    other server in the group.  With the exception of the
                    first server in a shared IP group, servers must be
                    launched into shared IP groups. A server may only be a
                    member of one shared IP group.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>social networking</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Joining groups and websites where you will find people with similar interests.
                    Individuals and businesses use social networks such as Facebook, Myspace and
                    Twitter to Share online experiences with others.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>subdomain</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A domain within a parent domain.  Subdomains cannot be registered. Subdomains
                    allow you to delegate domains. Subdomains can themselves have subdomains, so
                    third-level, fourth-level, fifth-level, and deeper levels of nesting are
                    possible. </para>
                <para>Subdomains are domains within a parent domain, and subdomains cannot be
                registered. Subdomains allow you to delegate domains. Subdomains can themselves have
                subdomains, so third-level, fourth-level, fifth-level, and deeper levels of nesting
                are possible. </para>
        </glossdef>
        </glossentry>   
        
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>T</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>U</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>V</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>virtual IP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A virtual IP is an Internet Protocol (IP) address configured on the load balancer
                    for use by clients connecting to a service that is load balanced. Incoming
                    connections are distributed to back-end nodes based on the configuration of the load
                    balancer. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>virus</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Harmful piece of computer programming that interferes with normal computer and
                    internet operations.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>W</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>X</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>Y</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
    <glossdiv>
        <title>Z</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm/>
            <glossdef>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <!-- ... -->
</glossary>
